

### CONTATTI

- **9** M
  - Milan, Italy
- carini.luca@icloud.com
- in
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/luca-carini-726473130/
- https://lucacarini.it

#### SKILLS

- •••• Collaboration & Teamwork
- •••• Ability to Work Under Pressure
- • • Creativity
- ●●● Adaptability
- • • Fast Learner
- •••• Java
- • • Javascript
- •••• Reactjs
- •••• CSS <sup>1</sup>
- •••• SQL
- • • Database NoSQL
- •••• Realtional Database
- •••• C
- •••• Docker
- •••• Kubernetes

### LANGUAGES

- •••• Italian
- ••• English
- ••• Spanish

### HOBBIES

I play various amateur sports such as tennis, soccer and running. Indeed I have been playing guitar for about 15 years and I'm crazy about it, I have started recording my improv and learning how to remix them. I love going out for a walk, reading and listening to music. I love to keep myself informed about new technologies and develop some little projects in order to make some hands on experience on what I learn.

# LUCA CARINI

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

During university, I have started working in a software house as a junior developer, in order to make some experience on what I have learned from my studies.

I have been working for almost 3 years now, mainly in large companies, where I have learnt a lot both on a technical and human prospective.

I am looking for an opportunity where I can put all that I have learnt, to work for a mission I'm passionate about.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Polytechnic University of Milan

Computer Engineering September 2015 - February 2019

### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# Backend Engineer Specialist Nexi S.p.a. | January 2022 - Now

Initially I worked in a team on a solution for online and mobile pos payments, developed in javaEE, deployed on a server with wildfly11 installed and managing the new developments, the application maintenance part and the relationship with the customer.

Later I was introduced to a new project, that was about rewriting a solution developed in a monolith architecture, into a microservices one, with spring boot, istio, docker and kubernetes.

I'm also covering the role of technical lead, managing a team of four resources, the relationships with the customers and the estimates for the various projects.

### Technologies:

Java 11 / Junit / Spring Boot / Microservices Architecture / Mockito / API / Oracle Database / PostgreSql / IntelliJ / Git / Jira / Docker / Kubernetes / Istio

# Application Development Accenture Technology S.r.l. | May 2021 - January 2022

Worked mainly in three industries, public and banking one. Public sector industry, implemented a java-based web app to to manage all orders for work uniforms

Public sector industry, developed a system to manage all the new procurement contracts.

Banking industry, developed a system for managing accounts and who, among the bank's customers, can afford a bank loan, following the client requirements.

### Technologies:

Java 11 / Junit / Spring Boot / Kafka / Microservices Architecture / Mockito / API / Spring MVC / Javascript / CSS / Jsp / Oracle Database / Eclipse / Git

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

### Consultant

### Deloitte Consulting S.r.l. | September 2019 - May 2021

Worked on implementing a scheduled java interface that runs on a Microsoft Server that manages an integration between the deloitte's ERP system and an external platform, to handle all the invoices' flow. The connection between the interface and the external system, was made by a SFTP connection. Worked on implementing a scheduled java interface that runs on a Microsoft Server that manages an integration between the deloitte's ERP system and an external SAP platform, to handle all the expenses' flow. During this project, I have worked closely with the data team, in order to create all the views/reports to allow the data analyst team to integrate everything with glik. The connection between the interface and the external system, was made by a SFTP connection. Worked on implementing a new HR system, that allows all the people in the HR team manage the whole employer's lifetime, from the hiring process, to the resignation one. During this project, I have worked closely with all the HR team, in order to take all the requirements and managed the presentation of the software and the related UATs.

Worked on a project that involves all the deloitte's IT team, the goal was moving from JDEdwards ERP to a SAP S/4 HANA. The team where I was scheduled, had the task of analyzing all the deloitte's internal flows (as-is) and then thinking how to integrate all of that with the new ERP's flows. During this project, we have worked closely with all the deloitte's Business Unit, in order to discuss with them on how the data will flow in the new system. We had to modify also the DB structures/procedures/views to maintain the correct functioning of the flows.

### Technologies:

Java 8 / SQL Database / Relational DB / JDBC / Jsch / IntelliJ / SQL Server Management Studio/ Java Sring Boot / Thymeleaf / Javascript / Junit / Visual Basic Script / Microsoft Server / Mulesoft / Git

# Junior Software Developer - Intern Faber System S.r.l. | September 2018 - July 2019

Worked as a junior developer, helping the R&D team, implementing new functionality to the platform that the company has developed to manage and archive all the clients' invoices.

### Technologies:

C# / Visual Studio / SQL Server Management Studio / Relational Database